BIO

Jonathan Berger is a designer, developer and technologist who has been active in the NYC technology scene since 2005, helping to organize events like the Agile Experience Design Meetup, the Pivotal Labs Tech Talk series in NY, Startup Weekend, Barcamp, Fashioncamp, and IgniteNYC. As a consultant he's been on the team with almost 30 startups and enterprises in the past few years, and spends his days building 1) software and 2) an agile design practice at Pivotal Labs. As a startup founder he helped build Market Publique, an online vintage fashion marketplace and community. Prior to that, he earned a Bachelors in Philosophy at Vassar College and a Masters in Media Studies at the New School (where he also spent quite a bit of time at Parson's Design + Technology program). He has worked as a designer, developer, video editor, animator, and technology consultant for institutions as diverse as Eyebeam, MTV Networks, Yahoo!, Ogilvy, and the American Museum of Natural History.

He is an internationally sought speaker who speaks about startups, technology, Lean, and Agile at events like LeanUX NYC, Agile UX NYC, Agile 2013, Future of Web Design, O'Reilly's Web 2.0 Expo, New York Tech Meetup, Fashion 2.0 Startup Showcase, Startup Weekend, North Brooklyn Breakfast Club, The Product Group, and others.

SELECTED WORK EXPERIENCE

Associate Director of Product Design, Pivotal Labs, NY, NY 2008-present.

Leading a team of ~10 designers, building an agile design practice and methodology.

Building web and mobile applications using Agile, XP, and Test-Driven methodologies.

Every day I code, design, anchor teams, lead inceptions, manage reports, and help run the office.

At Pivotal I've also been a Designer, Engineering Manager, and Design Manager.

Designer, American Museum of Natural History, NY, NY 2007-2008

Developed animations and motion graphics for the the Interactive division of the Exhibitions department for the *Horses* and *Hall of Human Origins* shows.

Video Editor & Technology Consultant, MTV Networks, NY, NY 2006-2007

Edited and animated video, designed work protocols & archiving systems, and wrote documentation for TVLand.com.

Teacher's Assistant, New School University, 2005-2006

Assisted professors Kit Laybourne (Producer's Craft), Ramu Dhara (Digital Design) and Mark Reilly (Fundamentals of Media Design). Provided technical assistance to students, set up class wikis and other infrastructure, videorecorded classes, assisted professors, and taught in their absence.

SKILLS

Expert in Agile, Lean Startup, and Extreme Programming (XP) methodologies.

Experienced product designer, with a strong emphasis on User Experience (UX).

Experienced with modern web development tools including Ruby, Javascript, HTML, CSS, and shell scripting. Adobe Certified Expert in Photoshop.

Extremely high level of proficiency in Vim, Adobe Creative Suite, AfterEffects, Final Cut Studio.

Years of experience with Microsoft Office, OpenOffice, Filemaker and various productivity applications. Extensive photography and videography production and post-production experience for broadcast and internet.

EDUCATION

New School University, NY, NY
Master of Arts in Media Studies, 2007

Vassar College, Poughkeepsie, NY Bachelor of Arts in Philosophy, 2001

PUBLIC SPEAKING & REFERENCES

Portfolio of talks at http://www.jonathanpberger.com/talks, references available upon request.